<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sig-network on Kubernetes Community</title>
    <link>/keps/sig-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sig-network on Kubernetes Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/keps/sig-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduate CoreDNS to GA</title>
      <link>/keps/sig-network/0010-20180314-coredns-ga-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/keps/sig-network/0010-20180314-coredns-ga-proposal/</guid>
      <description>Graduate CoreDNS to GA Table of Contents  Summary Motivation  Goals Non-Goals  Proposal  User Cases  Graduation Criteria Implementation History  Summary CoreDNS is sister CNCF project and is the successor to SkyDNS, on which kube-dns is based. It is a flexible, extensible authoritative DNS server and directly integrates with the Kubernetes API. It can serve as cluster DNS, complying with the dns spec. As an independent project, it is more actively developed than kube-dns and offers performance and functionality beyond what kube-dns has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPVS Load Balancing Mode in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>/keps/sig-network/0011-ipvs-proxier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/keps/sig-network/0011-ipvs-proxier/</guid>
      <description>IPVS Load Balancing Mode in Kubernetes Note: This is a retroactive KEP. Credit goes to @m1093782566, @haibinxie, and @quinton-hoole for all information &amp;amp; design in this KEP.
Important References: https://github.com/kubernetes/community/pull/692/files
Table of Contents  Summary Motivation  Goals Non-goals  Proposal  Kube-Proxy Parameter Changes Build Changes Deployment Changes Design Considerations IPVS service network topology Port remapping Falling back to iptables Supporting NodePort service Supporting ClusterIP service Supporting LoadBalancer service Session Affinity Cleaning up inactive rules Sync loop pseudo code  Graduation Criteria Implementation History Drawbacks Alternatives  Summary We are building a new implementation of kube proxy built on top of IPVS (IP Virtual Server).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pod Ready&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>/keps/sig-network/0007-pod-ready&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/keps/sig-network/0007-pod-ready&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>Pod Ready++ Table of Contents  Table of Contents Summary Motivation  Goals Non-Goals  Proposal  Implementation Details/Notes/Constraints Risks and Mitigations  Graduation Criteria Implementation History Alternatives  Summary This proposal aims to add extensibility to pod readiness. Besides container readiness, external feedback can be injected into PodStatus and influence pod readiness. Thus, achieving pod “ready++”.
Motivation Pod readiness indicates whether the pod is ready to serve traffic. Pod readiness is dictated by kubelet with user specified readiness probe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switch CoreDNS to the default DNS</title>
      <link>/keps/sig-network/0012-20180518-coredns-default-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/keps/sig-network/0012-20180518-coredns-default-proposal/</guid>
      <description>Switch CoreDNS to the default DNS Table of Contents  Summary Goals Proposal  User Cases  Graduation Criteria Implementation History  Summary CoreDNS is now well-established in Kubernetes as the DNS service, with CoreDNS starting as an alpha feature from Kubernetes v1.9 to now being GA in v1.11. After successfully implementing the road-map defined here, CoreDNS is GA in Kubernetes v1.11, which can be installed as an alternate to kube-dns in tools like kubeadm, kops, minikube and kube-up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>