<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sig-azure on Kubernetes Community</title>
    <link>/sigs-and-wgs/sig-azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sig-azure on Kubernetes Community</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/sigs-and-wgs/sig-azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0018-20180711-azure-availability-zones</title>
      <link>/sigs-and-wgs/sig-azure/0018-20180711-azure-availability-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sigs-and-wgs/sig-azure/0018-20180711-azure-availability-zones/</guid>
      <description>kep-number: 18 title: Azure Availability Zones authors: - &amp;ldquo;@feiskyer&amp;rdquo; owning-sig: sig-azure participating-sigs: - sig-azure - sig-storage reviewers: - name: &amp;ldquo;@khenidak&amp;rdquo; - name: &amp;ldquo;@colemickens&amp;rdquo; approvers: - name: &amp;ldquo;@brendanburns&amp;rdquo; editor: TBD creation-date: 2018-07-11 last-updated: 2018-07-11
status: provisional Azure Availability Zones Table of Contents  Azure Availability Zones  Summary Scopes and Non-scopes Scopes Non-scopes AZ label format Cloud provider options Node registration Get by instance metadata Get by Go SDK LoadBalancer and PublicIP AzureDisk PVLabeler PersistentVolumeLabel StorageClass Appendix   Summary This proposal aims to add Azure Availability Zones (AZ) support to Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>charter</title>
      <link>/sigs-and-wgs/sig-azure/charter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sigs-and-wgs/sig-azure/charter/</guid>
      <description>SIG Azure Charter The following is a charter for the Kubernetes Special Interest Group for Azure. It delineates the roles of SIG leadership, SIG members, as well as the organizational processes for the SIG, both as they relate to project management and technical processes for SIG subprojects.
Roles SIG Chairs  Run operations and processes governing the SIG Seed members established at SIG founding Chairs MAY decide to step down at anytime and propose a replacement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>